<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distributed Computing on Programming Philosophy</title>
    <link>/tags/distributed-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distributed Computing on Programming Philosophy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 17:05:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/distributed-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>With a little help from my friends…</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-06-21_with-a-little-help-from-my-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 17:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-06-21_with-a-little-help-from-my-friends/</guid>
      <description>Consensus building in Computes.
Photo by Sidharth Bhatia on Unsplash
Sometimes you want to make sure your tasks create a consistent result before trusting the outcome. We’ve added a simple consensus mechanism in Computes. When used, you can set a threshold of how many matches are required. Let’s look at an example task with a consensus threshold of 2. This means 2 tasks would have to agree on the results before they become visible in your dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Native Binaries in Computes</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-06-20_run-native-binaries-in-computes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 05:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-06-20_run-native-binaries-in-computes/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Ash Edmonds on Unsplash
Thanks to the new whitelist and manifest features of Computes v14.0.0, we can now allow native binaries to run in your network. This allows you to create binaries that can access features that Docker may not offer, especially access to the GPU of the nodes in your Computes network.
This post will show you how to set up a manifest, whitelist, and binaries that can run as tasks on many different operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Computes with Whitelists and Manifests</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-06-20_protecting-computes-with-whitelists-and-manifests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 03:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-06-20_protecting-computes-with-whitelists-and-manifests/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Mike Szczepanski on Unsplash
We’ve added whitelists to Computes to help you protect your network against malicious or unwanted task execution. You will need to run version 14.0.0 or higher to get the new whitelist functionality. If you want to get up and running quickly and explore the whitelists later, check out the Getting Startedguide to set up an open whitelist.### What’s changed?
There are two changes that will be immediately noticeable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling Computation from Data Transformation</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-03-07_decoupling-computation-from-data-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 13:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-03-07_decoupling-computation-from-data-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Peter Gabas on Unsplash
The Computes Mesh allows for some new ways of delivering applications. Computes helps you take advantage of idle CPU/GPU power you have sitting around in your network. In a traditional API setup, computations and data transformation are linked, usually deployed as an application running on a web server. Computes can help you decouple your computation from your API and provides new opportunities for data transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Infinity and Beyond!</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-01-02_to-infinity-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-01-02_to-infinity-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce I am officially co-founder and CTO of Computes, inc. I couldn’t be more excited to work on another startup with my partners in crime: @ChrisMatthieu, Roy van de Water, and Peter DeMartini. We are out to change the world, again!
I am eager to take on the CTO role again, especially given the incredibly ambitious dreams we have for Computes. Being at the intersection of emerging technologies and high-performing teams is where I love to be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>